Guide to the Rogan Jones Papers 1912-1983
Western Washington University, Heritage Resources
Rogan Jones Papers
1912-1983
1930-1970
Western Washington University Heritage Resources Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Goltz-Murray Building 808 25th St Bellingham, WA 98225-9123 Phone: 360 650 7747 Email: heritage.resources@wwu.edu http://library.wwu.edu/heritageresources
XOE_CPNWS0011rjones
Jones, Rogan.
15 linear ft.
The collection documents the activities and interests of radio and television broadcasting pioneer Lafayette Rogan Jones. Records span the period 1912-1983, with the bulk of materials dating from circa 1930-1970, and comprise subject files, clippings and scrapbooks, audio tapes and photographs.
Born in Memphis Tennesee on October 11, 1895, Lafayette Rogan Jones moved with his parents, Francis Goodbar Jones and Mary Rogan Jones to Boston in 1901, and then to Aberdeen, Washington in 1906. He attended private schools in Boston, public schools in Aberdeen and spent one year at Columbia University where he studied business. Jones lived in Aberdeen intermittently until 1930. Jones acquired his first radio station, KXRO, in Aberdeen, Washington in 1928, and purchased KVOS in Bellingham, Washington the following year. In addition to these stations, Jones owned KPQ radio in Wenatchee and KPCB in Seattle.
A pioneer in his field, Jones often generated conflict through his attempts to expand the interests and role of radio broadcasters and attract larger audiences. The legal case KVOS v Associated Press (circa 1934-1936) comprised one of the most noteworthy legal battles of his career. Responding to refusals by the Associated Press, the United Press, and the International News Service to sell news copy to radio stations, Jones and KVOS rewrote and then broadcast information found in newspapers. Accusing Jones of “news piracy”, local newspapers such as the Bellingham Herald and national news organizations including the Associated Press filed suit against KVOS. In 1936, the US Supreme Court decided in favor of KVOS, allowing for greater access by radio broadcasters to news sources (including sporting events), and paving the way towards the sale of information by news organizations to radio.
During the 1950s, Jones attracted further controversy through his creation of International Good Music (IGM), a centralized service providing recorded music and radio shows for broadcast across the world. In 1964, the Amercian Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (ASCAP) sued IGM and recipient stations, arguing that IGM broadcast music without their permission or that of the artists. The case was decided in favor of the IGM and other defendents. Having established himself in radio, Jones soon expanded his professional interests to include television, creating one of the first commercial cable systems in Bellingham, Washington. His first TV station, KVOS-TV, aired its first broadcast on May 23, 1953. Jones also founded cable television station, KPQ-CA in Wenatchee in 1953, before selling the station the following year. The British Columbia company Wometco eventually bought KVOS in 1962. Rogan Jones died on 27 April, 1972 in Bellingham, Washington.
The Rogan Jones papers document the activities and interests of radio and television broadcasting pioneer Lafayette Rogan Jones. Records span the period 1912-1983, with the bulk of materials dating from circa 1930-1970. Alphabetical subject files generated and maintained by Jones reflect his interests and involvement in radio and television broadcasting on a regional and national level. Subject files include materials relating to the legal case KVOS vs. Associated Press (concerning broadcasters’ rights to access and present news information to their audience), and Jones’ conflicts with bodies such the American Society of Composers, Artists and Performers regarding the management, licensing and operation of his stations. A large number of the subject files pertain to the operation and programming for KVOS radio station in Bellingham, Washington. Jones’ files also contain a small amount personal correspondence, dated 1912-1959 (the bulk of Jones’ personal and family records were removed before their donation to the Center for Pacific Northwest Studies).
The collection contains clippings and scrapbooks compiled by Jones through the period circa 1930-1958, documenting issues relating to radio broadcasting and also to news events affecting the Bellingham area. The bulk of material in the scrapbooks is compiled from Bellingham newspapers. The collection also includes reel-to-reel tapes containing select KVOS radio interviews and broadcasts (dated 1938-1940) and a small amount of photographic material.
The Rogan Jones Papers was organized in accordance with the following series arrangement:
Series I: Subject Files 1912-1983 (1930-1959)
Series II: Scrapbooks and Clippings 1930 - 1958
Series III: Audio Materials 1938-1970, undated
Subseries 1 - Reel to Reel Tapes, circa 1938-1970
Subseries 2 - Cassette Tapes, 1970
Series IV: Visual Materials 1982, undated.
The collection is open to the public.
Catherine Jones donated her late husband's papers to the Center for Pacific Northwest Studies in 1975.
The KVOS Film Records at the Center for Pacific Northwest Studies includes reel to reel films of KVOS Channel 12 programs filmed in the early to mid 1960s.
Richard M. Donnelly American Television for a Canadian Audience: Rogan Jones and the Establishment of KVOS-TV. (M.A. Thesis, University of Nebraska, 2009)
* Copy available in CPNWS Reference Library (in-house use only)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Jones, Rogan. --Archives.
KVOS-TV (Television station: Bellingham, Wash.)
Broadcasting -- Washington (State) -- Bellingham.; Broadcasting -- Law and legislation -- United States.; Radio stations -- Washington (State).
Journalism; Sound Recordings
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Subject Files, 1912-1983; 1930-1958; Series I
  - Advertising, 1940-1954 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Advertising Research Bureau Incorporated, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Advertising Research Bureau Incorporated, 1950 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Advertising Research Bureau Incorporated, 1951 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Advertising Research Bureau Incorporated, 1952 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - American Broadcasting Company, 1946-1950 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers (ASCAP), 1947-1949 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers (ASCAP), 1957-1959 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Associated Press, 1951-1956 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Associated Program Services, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Bellingham Athletic Club, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Bellingham Chamber of Commerce, 1951-1958 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Bellingham Charter, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Bellingham, Port of: Citizen Advisory Committee, 1951 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Bone, Homer T. (U.S. Senator), 1937 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Boundary Centennial Celebration, 1946 (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Broadcast Advertising Bureau, 1950-1955 (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Broadcast Magazine, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Broadcast Measurement Bureau, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Broadcast Music Incorporated, 1951-1956 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - Broadcasting Stations, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - Cable Accounts, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Channel 12 Ltd., 1954-1955 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Channel 12 Ltd., 1955 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Columbia Broadcasting Service, 1953-1958 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Columbia T.V. Service, 1958 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Craney, Ed., 1951-1952 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Davis, Kenneth, 1949-1956 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Dill, Clarence (U.S. Senator), 1936-1937 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Dumont Network, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Eastman Kodak, 1954 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Employment/Employees, 1940-1954 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Employment/Employees, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Equipment, Radio, 1944-1949 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Farris, Stultz, Bull, and Farris, 1953 (Box-folder 3/15)
  - Federal Communications Commission (FCC), 1943-1951 (Box-folder 3/16)
  - Ferry, 1951 (Box-folder 3/17)
  - Forjoe and Company, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Forjoe and Company, 1955 (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Forjoe and Company, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Frederick Ziv Company, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Fuller, Romig, 1950 (Box-folder 4/5)
  - General Electric, 1955 (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Graybar Mortgage Company, 1937 (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Guy, Bill, 1937 (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Haley, Andrew, 1947 (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Haley, Andrew, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Haley, Andrew, 1950 (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Haley, Andrew, 1951 (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Haley, Andrew, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Haley, Andrew, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Haley, Andrew, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Haley, Andrew: Photographs, 1946 (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Horace N. Stovin Company, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 5/5)
  - Horace N. Stovin Company, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 5/6)
  - Independent Broadcasters, 1949-1956 (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Insurance, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 5/8)
  - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, 1937-1954 (Box-folder 5/9)
  - International Good Music, 1958-1964 (Box-folder 5/10)
  - International Good Music: Receivership Dispute, 1963 (Box-folder 5/11)
  - International House, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 5/12)
  - International News Service, 1940 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - International Peace Arch Program Association, circa 1940 (Box-folder 6/1)
  - International Peace Arch Program Association, 1940-1945 (Box-folder 6/2)
  - International Peace Arch Program Association, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 6/3)
  - International Peace Arch Program Association, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 6/4)
  - International Peace Arch Program Association, 1950-1955 (Box-folder 6/5)
  - International Peace Arch Program Association, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 6/6)
  - International Peace Arch Program Association, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 6/7)
  - International Telemeter Corporation, 1953 (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Jackson, Henry (U.S. Senator), 1952-1958 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Jerrold Electronics Corporation, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Jerrold Electronics Corporation v. KVOS and Westcoast, 1964 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Jones, Rogan
    - Accident, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Accident, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Accounts, 1940-1947 (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Biographical Material, circa 1956-1958 (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Correspondence
      - General A-F, circa 1937-1957 (Box-folder 7/6)
      - General G-M, circa 1937-1957 (Box-folder 7/7)
      - General N-Z, circa 1937-1957 (Box-folder 7/8)
      - International, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 7/9)
      - Personal, 1912-1939 (Box-folder 7/10)
      - Personal, 1940-1954 (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Final Disposition of Papers, undated (Box-folder 7/12)
    - Mother's Estate, 1955 (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Speeches, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 8/1 - 8/3)
    - Taxes and Financial Statements, 1947-1957 (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Trips, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Trip to Russia, 1958 (Box-folder 8/6)
  - KDZR, 1922 (Box-folder 9/1)
  - KELA, 1940; 1951 (Box-folder 9/2)
  - KFPM, 1930 (Box-folder 9/3)
  - KGIR, 1937-1940 (Box-folder 9/4)
  - KING, 1950 (Box-folder 9/5)
  - KMO, 1937-1950 (Box-folder 9/6)
  - KOL, 1940-1949 (Box-folder 9/7)
  - KPQ
    - 50 kw, 1957 (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Cole Wylie, 1936-1939 (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1956 (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Jim Wallace, 1946-1951 (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Jim Wallace, 1952-1956 (Box-folder 9/12)
    - Jim Wallace, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 9/13)
    - Staff Investment and Profit Share, 1948-1952 (Box-folder 9/14)
    - T.V. and Community Antenna, 1952-1955 (Box-folder 9/15)
    - T.V. and Community Antenna, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 9/16)
    - Transmitter Fire, August 7, 1967 (Box-folder 9/17)
  - KPUG, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 9/18)
  - KVI, 1940-1944 (Box-folder 10/1)
  - KVOS Files
    - Accounts, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Accounts, 1948 (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Accounts: Collection Notices, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Board of Directors Meetings: Minutes, 1940-1947 (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Correspondence (general), 1936-1947 (Box-folder 10/6)
    - Correspondence (general), 1948-1949; 1953 (Box-folder 10/7)
    - Discrepancy Reports, 1955 (Box-folder 10/8)
    - Insurance, 1948-1955 (Box-folder 10/9)
    - Legal Suits
      - KVOS v. Associated Press (correspondence), 1935-1937 (Box-folder 10/10)
      - KVOS v. Associated Press (legal), 1935-1937 (Box-folder 10/11)
      - Licensing Suit (correspondence), 1936-1937 (Box-folder 10/12)
      - Licensing Suit (legal), 1936-1937 (Box-folder 10/13)
      - Miscellaneous Suits (correspondence), 1936-1952 (Box-folder 11/1)
      - Miscellaneous Suits (legal), 1936-1952 (Box-folder 11/2)
    - New Building
      - Blueprints and Reports, 1955 (Box-folder 11/3)
      - Correspondence, 1955 (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Programming (General Files), 1933-1939 (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Programming (General Files), 1940 (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Programming (General Files), 1950-1951 (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Programming (General Files), 1952-1955 (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Programming (General Files), 1956-1958 (Box-folder 11/9)
    - Programming - America's Great Story, 1950 (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Programming - Around the World Press Conference Program, 1958 (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Programming - Around the World Contest (trip), 1958 (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Programming - Best Program Contest, 1937 (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Programming - Buchan's Musical Tune-O, 1937 (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Programming - Count Bellingham's Blessings, 1952 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Programming - Dinner Bell Hour, 1952 (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Programming - Education, 1937-1958 (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Programming - Foreign Programming, 1949-1958 (Box-folder 12/9)
    - Programming - Foreign Students, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 12/10)
    - Programming - Forum Magazine, 1956 (Box-folder 12/11)
    - Programming - GO (Grand Opening) Day, 1953 (Box-folder 12/12)
    - Programming - Lebanese Records, 1957 (Box-folder 12/13)
    - Programming - Music, 1940 (Box-folder 12/14)
    - Programming - News, 1951-1958 (Box-folder 12/15)
    - Programming - Newspaper-of-the-Air, 1937 (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Programming - Operation Good Neighbor, 1957 (Box-folder 13/2)
    - Programming - Overseas Television Project, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 13/3)
    - Programming - Pacific Mid-Eastern High School Forum, 1956 (Box-folder 13/4)
    - Programming - Public Service, 1937-1947 (Box-folder 13/5)
    - Programming - Public Service, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 13/6)
    - Programming - Public Service, 1951-1958 (Box-folder 13/7)
    - Programming - Raw Transcripts, 1934 April-August (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Programming - Raw Transcripts, 1934 September– October (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Programming - Raw Transcripts, 1934 November (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Programming - Raw Transcripts, 1934 December (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Programming - Raw Transcripts, 1935 January – February (Box-folder 14/5)
    - Programming - Raw Transcripts, 1935 March-May (Box-folder 14/6)
    - Programming - Raw Transcripts, 1935 June-July (Box-folder 14/7)
    - Programming - Raw Transcripts, 1935 August (Box-folder 15/1)
    - Programming - Raw Transcripts, 1935 September (Box-folder 15/2)
    - Programming - Raw Transcripts, 1935 October–December (Box-folder 15/3)
    - Programming - Rocky Marciano, 1961
      - Publicity and clippings (Box-folder 15/4)
      - Photographs (Box-folder 15/5)
    - Programming - Sports, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Programming - Sports, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Programming - Sports, High School, 1957 (Box-folder 16/3)
    - Programming - Sunday Broadcasters, 1949 (Box-folder 16/4)
    - Programming - World Wide Neighbors, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Radio, AM
      - Advertising, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 16/6)
      - Construction Requests, 1937; 1943 (Box-folder 16/7)
      - Equipment and Engineering, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 16/8)
      - Telephone Transmission Charge (Contract), 1936-1937 (Box-folder 16/9)
    - Radio, FM, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 16/10)
    - Sales, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 16/11)
    - Sales, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 16/12)
    - Staff Memorandum, 1940-1949 (Box-folder 16/13)
    - Staff Memorandum, 1950-1955 (Box-folder 16/14)
    - Staff Memorandum, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 16/15)
    - Stock Ownership Contracts, 1937 (Box-folder 17/1)
    - Tri-County Directory, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 17/2)
  - KVOS TV
    - Cable, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 17/3)
    - Cable, 1953 (Box-folder 17/4)
    - Cable Accounts, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 17/5)
    - Canada, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 17/6)
    - Canada, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 17/7)
    - Canada: De West, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 17/8)
    - Community Antenna, undated (Box-folder 18/1)
    - Community Antenna, Weekly Reports, 1953 (Box-folder 18/2)
    - Deal, 1954 (Box-folder 18/3)
    - Deal, Memo Re: Possible Sale, 1960 June 17 (Box-folder 18/4)
    - Equipment and Engineering, Duplicating, 1955 (Box-folder 18/5)
    - Equipment and Engineering, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 18/6)
    - Equipment and Engineering, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 18/7)
    - Equipment and Engineering, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 18/8)
    - Financing (Prospective Sales), 1955 (Box-folder 18/9)
    - General, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 18/10)
    - KPUG Conflict, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 18/11)
    - New Transmitter Site, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 18/12)
    - New Transmitter Site, 1954-1958 (Box-folder 18/13)
  - Lincoln County Broadcasters, 1949-1952 (Box-folder 18/14)
  - Magnuson, Warren (U.S. Senator), 1948-1958 (Box-folder 18/15)
  - Mayor's Ferry Committee, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Military Tours, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 19/2)
  - Miller, Ralph, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Mintz, David, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 19/4)
  - Miscellaneous material, undated (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Mount Vernon, 1940 (Box-folder 19/6)
  - Mutual Broadcasting Company, 1940-1950 (Box-folder 19/7)
  - National Association of Broadcasters, 1935-1937 (Box-folder 19/8)
  - National Association of Broadcasters, 1940-1952 (Box-folder 19/9)
  - National Association of Radio and Television Broadcasters, 1952 (Box-folder 19/10)
  - National Broadcasting Company, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 19/11)
  - Northwest Washington District Fair, 1940 (Box-folder 19/12)
  - Olympia, 1946-1950 (Box-folder 19/13)
  - Pacific Broadcasting Company, 1940 (Box-folder 19/14)
  - Pacific National Exhibit, 1950 (Box-folder 19/15)
  - Pacific Telephone and Telegraph, 1940; 1954 (Box-folder 19/16)
  - Pemberton, William H. (Judge), 1936-1937 (Box-folder 19/17)
  - Politics, 1934-1951 (Box-folder 20/1)
  - Programming Services, 1940-1949 (Box-folder 20/2)
  - Radio Corp of America, 1936-1957 (Box-folder 20/3)
  - Radio Daily (Publication), 1940; 1953 (Box-folder 20/4)
  - Radio Stations- Construction Requests, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 20/5)
  - Radio Stations- General Correspondence, 1936-1954 (Box-folder 20/6)
  - Rainier Broadcasting Company, 1940-1947 (Box-folder 20/7)
  - Reeves, Hal, 1952 (Box-folder 20/8)
  - Reid, Gordon, 1955 (Box-folder 20/9)
  - Retail Counselors Incorporated, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 20/10)
  - Robert Meeker Association Incorporated, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 20/11)
  - Rotary Clubs, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 20/12)
  - Rotary Clubs- Foreign Student Scholarship, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 20/13)
  - SESAC, 1950-1956 (Box-folder 20/14)
  - Sackett, Sheldon, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 20/15)
  - Schellenbach, Lewis (U.S. Senator), 1940 (Box-folder 20/16)
  - Seifrit, Charles (Chuck)- The Bellingham Herald, 1946-1951 (Box-folder 20/17)
  - Special Copyright Fund, undated (Box-folder 20/18)
  - Surveys, 1946-1951 (Box-folder 21/1)
  - Surveys, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 21/2)
  - TV Incorporated, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 21/3)
  - Tacoma Narrows Bridge, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 21/4)
  - Taft and Warner Incorporated- Incorporation Papers, 1924 (Box-folder 21/5)
  - Television- General Correspondence, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 21/6)
  - Transradio Press, 1940 (Box-folder 21/7)
  - U.S. Broadcasting Company
    - Advertising Items, 1930 (Box-folder 21/8)
    - Bulletin and Franchise, 1930 (Box-folder 21/9)
    - District Plan Organization and Shipping Documents, undated (Box-folder 21/10)
    - General Correspondence, 1929 November-December (Box-folder 21/11)
    - General Correspondence, 1930 January (Box-folder 22/1)
    - General Correspondence, 1930 February (Box-folder 22/2)
    - General Correspondence, 1930 March (Box-folder 22/3)
    - General Correspondence, 1930 April (Box-folder 22/4)
    - General Correspondence, 1930 May (Box-folder 23/1)
    - General Correspondence, 1930 June (Box-folder 23/2)
    - General Correspondence, 1930 July (Box-folder 23/3)
    - General Correspondence, 1930 August (Box-folder 23/4)
    - General Correspondence, undated (Box-folder 23/5)
    - Program Records, undated; 1930 (Box-folder 23/6)
    - Prospectus, 1930 (Box-folder 23/7)
    - Radio Franchise Applications, 1930 (Box-folder 23/8)
    - Station Questionnaires, undated (Box-folder 23/9)
  - U.S. Congress, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 23/10)
  - U.S. Congress- House Resolution 7062, 1952 (Box-folder 23/11)
  - U.S. Congress- Senate Bills 217 218 (Copyright Law), 1937 (Box-folder 23/12)
  - U.S. Congress- Senate Radio Correspondent’s Gallery, 1940 (Box-folder 23/13)
  - U.S.S. Hancock (CVA-19), 1954 (Box-folder 24/1)
  - U.S.S.R., 1957-1958 (Box-folder 24/2)
  - Unions, 1936-1950 (Box-folder 24/3)
  - United Press, 1948-1958 (Box-folder 24/4)
  - Universal Publishers, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 24/5)
  - Vickers, Loyal, 1957 (Box-folder 24/6)
  - Wallgren, Mongram C., 1930 (Box-folder 24/7)
  - Washington State Association of Broadcasters, 1936-1947 (Box-folder 24/8)
  - Washington State Association of Broadcasters, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 24/9)
  - Washington State Association of Broadcasters, 1951-1954 (Box-folder 24/10)
  - Washington State Association of Broadcasters, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 24/11)
  - Washington State Radio News Bureau, 1948-1954 (Box-folder 24/12)
  - Westcoast Broadcasters, 1929-1954 (Box-folder 24/13)
  - Westcoast Broadcasters- Profit, Loss, Balance, 1928-1932 (Box-folder 24/14)
  - Westcoast Broadcasters- Stockholders Meeting, 1929-1939 (Box-folder 24/15)
  - Wometco, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 25/1)
  - Wometco- Annual Report, 1981 (Box-folder 25/2)
  - Wometco- KVOS, TV 12- British Columbia, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 25/3)
- Clippings and Scrapbooks, 1930 - 1958; Series II
  - Clippings, 1930s-1950s (Box-folder 25/4)
  - Clippings re: war in Europe, 1939 (Box-folder 25/5)
  - Clipping: "Our Respects to Rogan Jones," Broadcasting Telecasting, 1953 September 7 (Box-folder 25/6)
  - Scrapbooks, 1933-1936 (Box-folder 26/1)
  - Scrapbooks, 1934 (Box-folder 26/2)
  - Scrapbooks, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 26/3)
  - Scrapbooks, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 26/4)
  - Scrapbooks, 1941-1947 (Box-folder 26/5)
  - Scrapbooks, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 26/6)
  - Scrapbooks, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 26/7)
  - Scrapbooks, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 26/8)
- Audio Materials, 1938-1970; undated; Series III
  - Reel to Reel Tapes, circa 1938-1970; Subseries 1
    - Wallace Campbell Speech "What Makes A City Clique", undated (Box-folder 27/1)
    - American National Anthem and Telephone Conversation of Jack Clark and Fair Representative, undated (Box-folder 27/1)
    - KVOS Radio-TV Operation 5000 Sound Track, undated (Box-folder 27/2)
    - South African Speaker, undated (Box-folder 27/2)
    - Peace Arch, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 27/3)
    - KPUG v. KVOS Debate For Channel 12, 1952 November 25 (Box-folder 27/3)
    - Rogan Jones Washington Club speech re: USSR, 1958 (Box-folder 27/4)